My 1525, the Education by Master 1 Church, Mr. Ergo.
Mr. Speaker, Mr. Speaker, Mr. Speaker.
Oh, again we are so grateful for this day that you've given us.
We thank you for our city.
We're going to pray for our leaders now as they make decisions and choices.
We pray for our families God that they would be blessed in our community
and then more and more businesses will bring jobs for Jari and pray that Jesus Christ.
Amen.
Congratulations to the fire at the United States of America,
and to the Republic for which it stands.
One nation, another God, individual, with liberty and justice for all.
So, for both of the giftletons, good and personal experiences.
Five plainblists.
Motion to approve.
Second, accept.
Five.
Six.
Ten.
Two.
One.
Five.
Ten.
Six.
Five.
Four.
Head.
for Crystal in Jennifer.
Actually, we're going to let Chris do his audit presentation, Chris is with the HTC
CPAs, and he was our auditor this year.
Welcome, Chris.
Thank you for having me.
Chris, I'm with HTC CPAs, and we are firm to form the audit for June 30, 2024.
So what I'm going to do is I'm going to go for these three reports, which is audit.
I'll go over those.
We have about a hundred pages here, but I won't go.
And the first paragraph, from page five, says that we have audited the accompanying financial statements.
The second paragraph states, in our opinion, the financial statements, refer to above, present fairly, in all material respects.
So that is our opinion paragraph.
That's what we engaged to do is putting a thing in all the financial statements.
What does that mean?
That means that a hundred pages that follow and be relied upon by veterans at that fair materialistic statements.
So the numbers that are engaged.
So that's what, that's what we've been in clean, clean report and that's the best opinion that we can offer.
I'm going to reference the third paragraph there that states that we did not,
that this my name is, my name, my industrial film.
So that is, that is presented in these financial statements,
however, it's audited by another firm, we rely on it.
So from there, this is a three-page audit report.
It states, what maintenance must be faulty is,
it states where our responsibility is, the main thing,
is that second paragraph, there's, is our audited thing.
So from there, how many go to things?
One, so I think 15 is the same thing.
Because the brief discussion on the changes in that position.
So this is your revenues and expenditures.
For June 30, 2024, compared with June 30, 2023.
So we're just going to hit a couple of highlights here.
Now, until seeing we have three different columns,
we have governmental activities, business type activities,
and then a total column, which is the total, for the government, that large.
So a couple of points point out within the governmental activities,
the 2024 column revenues did decrease by around $2 million.
That was due to a full-backed challenge.
Similarly, in the business type activities, total revenues,
those were also down, but that changes in that.
So then we'll look at expenses here.
Total expenses for the governmental activities,
in Greece, primarily due to operational expense,
had some grant expenses that we spent in 2024,
but also just operational expenses that increased over last year.
Look at the very bottom, changing that position.
That is essentially your profit.
24 miles, 23 miles.
Look at the total column that is 1.7 million in the 2024.
Compared to last year at 5.1, which again,
so that's a pretty high level of a condensed version
of the revenues and expenses for the city.
Compared to 20, go to page 24.
This is, I'm just going to like a general fund here,
and this is the balance sheet for the general fund.
So you have your cash and your sea pools up top,
liabilities in the middle of it,
but what I'm going to focus on is your fund balance for the general fund.
So you'll see the line on this as an assigned fund balance,
the unassigned fund balance, and the unwhite or the city.
And so you want to help the unassigned fund balance.
So what is healthy, what we look at,
about percentages, just like you would,
and we're just seeing what expenses a revenue is compared,
compared to those, different percentage of those.
10 to 30 percent is what we see.
You guys are setting around 15 percent of your general fund revenues
in the unassigned fund balance.
However, if you see the line this, right above the unassigned fund balance,
it says a signed 2.6 million.
The majority of that, and thank to 2.4 million of that,
is a signed in next year.
So you really have a higher unassigned fund balance.
So that's a, you combine the two, your close to 30 percent.
Just look at the special utility of your assets,
like billies, and then just looking at the bottom number there,
the unrestricted net position, you can't see them alert to what we just discussed.
You're at 10 million in understricted net position.
more expenditures, we're about 30 million revenues, and so you're about 33%.
Which, which is a healthy gift over about 75 pages there.
But it's not, it's not, it's not.
So the numbers that you just saw within the balance sheets, it just goes into more details.
So there's about 10 pages on what that specific.
So just more detail of the schedules that we just saw.
So on page 95, this is what we call a byproduct of what we do.
So this is a report on internal control.
Our goal is to put an opinion on the financial statements, which we did in that first report.
That, as you report on internal control, in compliance is a byproduct,
because as we're doing our procedures, as we're testing the balances,
it's something comes up that we think is finding and issue,
and we will bring it up in this report.
So the middle where it says report on internal controls over financial reporting,
we do have four findings, which we will discuss in a moment.
We did not have any time available, but those will be just here in a moment.
But we will discuss our third report.
And if you spin over seven or 50,000 federal expenditure,
you have what's called a federal fund.
So that's a lot different from a financial statement on it.
A financial statement on it, we're trying to get comfortable with the balances on the planning
of this cash state that reads what is your debt.
The federal audit that we're doing here is,
did you do with the federal grant policy?
for the compliance out that we did not have any issues with the court that the city of Miami.
On our two auditors report that we issued first one, going to page 100, we'll talk about findings.
Finding number one, the government, the government on a D should maintain adequate control to the cash,
including proper authorization, documentation, this first one for seniors and direct insolentation.
As we were doing our procedures, we discovered that there was withdraws, per cash, and distributed for a crisis with the city.
We didn't find any fraudulent.
It's just not documented where the transactions were distributed and then painted out to prize winners.
However, there's just no trail to track that.
Again, didn't find anything fraudulent where the money was withdrawn.
I think that it's not good for seniors.
Funding number two, the government organization should follow proper procurement procedures that include purchase records and purchase orders prior to committing to purchases and received.
So, this is just the first shorter process where it counsels that without the budget.
Then the department heads, then purchase orders, transactions, purchase records.
A lot of our testing and the transactions that have been solved, that it's a sequence of the dates.
We understand and this happens at a lot of cities where it does happen in voice
because but it got to, it seemed a little more than just those.
So, I'll move on to number three, which is a lot of big paragraphs there, but we'll just
the accounts receivable in the past.
There was accounts receivable balances that were coded to just
misling is revenue items and then not applied to accounts receivable still are presented correctly.
That total amount, however, not applied to the correct accounts and then offset by just a catch all account that nets it obviously.
But that's being corrected and point out.
So, then I'll go to the fourth on the next page, cash reconciliation.
So, this has been a discipline and it was just there's a difference in the cash reconciliation.
It carries over a similar difference.
It's just not the exact difference.
So, again, this is, we've had a lot of discussions regarding these findings.
The, I have confidence and they are in steps to each and every one of these shins.
summary, we did have four findings, but it is, it is a clean out of the court.
I don't question others though.
I said I don't question others, I mean involvement to me.
Confessions these where we owe evidence of fraud, or anyone doing anything, criminal, discussed with him, how he would.
My employees.
Yes.
Yeah.
I was like, we have a lot of them.
So, you know, there's a thing called them at the top when they definitely show them.
Thank you.
What's the action?
Just improving the out of findings?
Where is it?
Make a motion, may I prove the out?
It's that.
Hi.
Pardon, sign.
Thank you.
Hi.
Nine.
Discussion regarding a joint useful attachment management point there.
Leave me.
What is this?
Process.
We just come in.
I have to talk about this discusses.
I have to see us going.
Process.
If somebody wanted to do it.
So, what the process we look like is they apply for a permit if they need any cost of that
Make ready would be there'd be several things to be existing fee for a public aspect was that now
I'm gonna pay two dollars and you'll take six that's what our next item is
This would be the
This is the cost for us to make sure that they we end the business between our side therefore that's like 24
They look at the space to know what it's gonna and if there's other things to talk like
No, what's there now be grandfathered for?
Well, it doesn't necessarily have to be.
If it doesn't what this would be, you know, if they're not, if they're not, if they don't have to plan it, it's just over.
That's not the next place.
I mean, in case you think like FCC, FCC, they're actually looking at what this is like 60% of our days.
So, this would do contract and contract to do it for a slightly more.
So, that'd be anybody who say cable one for Sparklock.
If they're coming out, and they want to attach anything new to our poll, they have to come through first.
This is also kind of clean up to where we're wanting to go.
It would definitely help with that.
There's lots of ways you can do things.
Because I know we've talked about cleaning it up because of where we're wanting to go.
There's a lot of housing violations.
But there's a lot of old stuff that's done active, that's still in the polls, which is that in the way.
And which would be in the way if we're kind of having five wrong.
And if they want that they want to go to the right, we get if we actually have one.
Do we, you have a current poll inventory?
And so do you have like now that you know where your poles are and you have an inventory do you have a strategy for
Like auditing them just to check to see status and and I mean, that sounds like a lot of
Poles to have to manage but how do you manage to make sure that those that people aren't attaching things
unofficially and
Right
So I guess that's kind of my point like how do you how do you identify if somebody's
Been approved to attach to a pole
Like if you're driving around and you see somebody then you're gonna know, but
So if somebody's a vendor of ours and they are on our poles, do they notify us if they're coming to do work on them?
I guess I'm just trying to understand if we how do we identify if somebody's
Legitimately doing something or not
My house they process tickets and out their tech their tech rolls out so that's what you're needing to drop your house
How are we gonna know he's hanging that drop
Is that kind of what this plan is going for or specifically for the ingenuity of the polls?
So sorry, I don't know what I'm going to correct me, but would this plan that we're discussing with that include the points they brought up maybe like a
How would we would know and the future so that people there in our country are currently
So that's going to be a nice plan
If I know for a fact there's a lot of stuff on city polls that is either not active
That probably needs to go away
It's not our responsibility as a city to be a friend of it, but
Being 18 to your sparklight
There's a lot of stuff out there at the point I need to be there and that's close enough polls and probably won't call the problem
If we start, you know, putting by wrong
We're hoping this next action
I saw some polls that were upgraded over by the prognome park was that because of that reason
Well, that's actually have to do with it
Yeah, it was a lot of work
Pretty good to do that
That was a lot of work
For the city
Oh, they did
We were on number 9, basically we were on number 10,
but I've been gay from what he Lee,
law officer there, LSE, for representation
and consultation regarding
a having poll attachment agreement,
an authorized and trusted manager to sign.
So the city of coffee bill actually,
you're coffee bill power online,
it's actually I recommend it to her.
So it's kind of a niche market at appears
for like poll attachments and I can't even negotiate
with the different vendors.
So with this agenda,
we would kind of highlight we would pull
who hire her, you have a significant issue in actual
new poll attached to my channel with these vendors.
And it also gets in the game for what we do do our own
fiber, so that anybody else wants to come in and attach
our polls in and also be lying in the same field that we
could first day do what Derek was talking.
I've been through something very similar to this before.
When I worked for AT&T, and when both, we'll just get
ready to get in the fiber business, they, of course,
RAC polls and RAC on both, so they did the same thing with
their poll attached to my agreement, updated it, and they
went $10 per attachment.
It was a dollar per poll, and went to $10 per attachment.
When all the polls got cleaned up real quick, because they
came to eat them on a fake $10 per, so they had to go
out and strip and everything off the polls that wasn't working,
because each grew custom bucks, you know, each guy
bring custom bucks and everything, put in a custom
bucks, then bucks, then bucks, then bucks, then bucks.
So I went out and cleaned off every poll.
We spent a lot of time cleaning all the stuff off polls that
didn't need to be there.
So I'm not saying we're going to $10 per attachment.
But I'm just saying it works, because they don't want to pay
that extra.
Well, they know they got dead stuff there in the account.
And I think it needs to be per attachment and not
per poll.
Whatever the number is, because that's what that's what
hits them in the pocketbook and makes them go clean and low.
Because it adds that quick.
And there's a lot of attachments on there that don't need to be there.
The question is, so the fees associated
something you work for, so it's $350 an hour?
Yes, they're.
And her name's Penny.
Okay, I'll make a motion we approve.
Hi.
11.
The new business.
If any, which is risen, the residents are posting this agenda.
12 staff reports.
13 testing community announcements.
14 trust management communication.
I'm just at the board now that the company that we hired to design our
driver has started.
They'll actually be in town.
We're going to be up on the turn pack.
But we talked about maybe being an AT&T's office or someone who works so much.
If we get you now there may have heard from them.
But we've got to get on the turn pack to get really depend on going to get off of AT&T's
pipes that's there in the sense of office by all the morons.
Or you'd get off the first net, which is out on the turn pack.
Which first net might be a little more reliable.
Just because when everything else is down, they'll make sure it works first.
That's what I was going to say.
The building now to have you just call OK in the existing building.
If you're out there, you're going to build a building.
Build a hidden inside.
So what happens if AT&T ever abandoned that building?
That's what we're making a cheap offer for.
But I mean, if they sell it to somebody else, I was in impact as well.
I would say if they're selling it, that means they're pulling out of my home,
which means we'd have to buy us the supplies.
But the first net would probably be the one that wouldn't get rid of
because that brought us all their cellular or anything.
But we're going to get that pipe from someone.
And AT&T's already here.
Bulk's closed, but I don't know.
I've closed it over.
That's a lot of pipe to this.
So I think that's the main reason I'm going to.
I think that's the main reason.
Exactly.
You know, we go there, we're just trying to work with AT&T and see if we can go look at it.
All of it there.
And see, like, they want us to come to the current board.
If you're headed into that.
From, you know.
That was it is.
I think both selects would not want to grow, and it's going to be a boat from there.
And AT&T may not like it.
Let's call it okay.
And therefore it can people.
Let's thank customers.
I don't know.
But again, they're getting ready to pull out of a lot of areas around here anyway.
By the end of June of next year, they're supposed to pull it completely out of commerce,
quapal and after.
We shut everything, cough or off in those areas.
And my mold before behind that.
15.
This means what I'll be reading to me in the Council to review.
Give me in from Council chambers.
And in the staff room for the purpose of executive session.
That's the completion of the regular scheduled meeting of the Community Council.